# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道年菜
In this video, I'll share the recipe of a dish for Chinese New Year
# 扣肘子
Braised Pork Knuckle
# 首先我们准备猪前肘2个（每个约1000克）
Firstly, let's prepare two pork front knuckles (each around 1000g)
# 将肘子的皮烧至焦黑后再用温水清洗干净
Scortch the skin until it's burnt black and rinse it with warm water
# 同学们这一步的目的是破坏猪皮的汗腺去除腥味
The purpose of this step is to remove the odor of pork skin
# 也可以清洗干净之后再次烧黑再次清洗
We can also clean it and then burn and rinse again
# 二次处理可以更大限度的减少皮腥味
Applying this method twice can eliminate the bad smell more thoroughly
# 清洗干净之后开始准备辅料
After we cleaned it, we can start to prepare minor ingredient
# 准备生姜和大葱各50克
Prepare ginger and spring onions, each 50g
# 分别切成片和长段备用
Section them to thin pieces and slices and set them aside
# 碗中加入去籽草果2颗
Add two tsao-ko (seed removed) to the bowl
# 加入橘子皮1小块
Add a small piece of tangerine peel
# 加入八角2颗
Add two star anise
# 加入桂皮1小块
Add a small piece of cinnamon
# 加入香叶2片
Add two pieces of bay leaves
# 加入小茴香1小把（约10克）
Add a small handful of fennel seeds (around 10g)
# 加入几颗三奈
Add a few sand gingers
# 下一步开始初加工
Now we get started with the preliminary work
# 首先我们在锅中加入大半锅清水
Firstly, add water to the wok until it's half-full
# 然后将肘子冷水下锅焯水
Then put the pork knuckle in the cold water to parboil
# 中途再加入少许料酒
Add a little Chinese cooking wine midway
# 水开10分钟之后将肘子捞出
Drain the knuckle after the water boils for 10 minutes
# 下一步开始准备卤制
Next, prepare to braise
# 锅中加入植物油1大勺
Add a large spoon of vegetable oil to the wok
# 油温4成热之后将准备好的料头和香辣下锅
When the oil is heated to 40% done
# 然后开小火翻炒5分钟
Turn to low heat and stir fry for 5 minutes
# 中途加入1小把青花椒和干辣椒
Then add a small handful of Sichuan green peppercorn and dried chili pepper
# 所有辅料炒香之后加入一大锅清水
After all the minor ingredients are properly stir-fried, add plenty of water
# 然后将焯水的肘子下锅
and then put the parboiled knuckle into the wok
# 清水的量能没过肘子2厘米即可
You'll be fine as long as the water level is 2 centimeters above the knuckle
# 下一步开始调色和调味
Now let's prepare the sauce and color
# 锅中加入糖色30克
Add 30g of caramelized sugar to the wok
# 没有糖色的同学可以用老抽代替
If you don't have it, use dark soy sauce instead
# 加入生抽酱油50克
Add 50g of light soy sauce
# 加入冰糖1小块（约20克）
Add a small chunk of white rock sugar (around 20g)
# 加入食用盐5大勺（约22克）
Add five large spoons of salt (around 22g)
# 加入胡椒粉2大勺（约3克）
Add two large spoons of grounded pepper (around 3g)
# 然后转小火卤制90分钟
Turn on low heat and marinate for 90 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将肘子初步卤香入底味
The purpose of this step is to season the knuckle before we add more complicated flavors
# 90分钟之后将肘子捞出备用
After 90 minutes, drain the knuckle and set it aside
# 然后再次把锅烧热
Then preheat the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
After it's heated, add Kuan You (literally "broad oil")
# 油温5成热之后将肘子下锅炸6分钟
When the oil is 50% heated, start to fry the knuckle for 6 minutes
# 这一步的目的是减少肘子皮下的油脂和增香
The purpose of this step is to thin the fatty layer and enhance the knuckle's flavor
# 喜欢肥一些的同学可以忽略这一步
If you like the greasy flavor, ignore this step
# 6分钟之后将肘子捞出
After 6 minutes, drain the knuckle
# 下一步开始拆肘子
Next, we take the knuckle apart
# 首先将肘子切开之后取下中间的骨头
First, we cut the knuckle in half and take out the bone in the middle
# 同学们也可以待其凉透之后再操作以防烫手
You can wait until the temperature goes down so that it wouldn't hurt your hand
# 然后将肘子的皮和肉分离下来
Then separate the skin and meat of the knuckle
# 皮肉分离之后在内侧切上花刀
After the skin and meat are separated, cut on the inside following this pattern
# 切花刀的目的是方便用筷子夹开
The purpose of this pattern is to make it easy to take it apart with chopsticks
# 然后将肘子皮朝下垫在碗底
Then lay the knuckle skin in a bowl with outside touching the bottom
# 垫好之后将肘子的肉切成片
After laying it out, slice the knuckle meat
# 切好之后整齐的码放在碗中
Place the cutted meat orderly in the bowl
# 下一步开始调汁
Next, we prepare the sauce
# 碗中加入卤肘子的原汁大半碗
Add more than half a bowl of marinade
# 加入适量的食用盐
Add some salt
# 加入胡椒粉少许
Add a little grounded pepper
# 将调好的汁倒入碗中
Pour the prepared sauce to a bowl
# 碗中加入适量的生姜片
Add some sliced ginger to the bowl
# 加入几颗花椒
Add a few Sichuan peppercorns
# 加入八角1颗
Add one star anise
# 加入干辣椒3个
Add three dried chili pepper
# 然后放入蒸锅中
And put it in the pot for steaming
# 加入小葱1根增香
Add a green onion to enhance the flavor
# 大火烧开之后转中小火蒸2个小时
After the water boils, switch to medium/low heat and steam for two hours
# 2个小时之后将肘子取出倒出汁水
After two hours, take the knuckle out and pour out the liquid
# 然后把肘子倒扣在碗里面
Place the knuckle up-side-down in the bowl
# 下一步开始准备淋汁
Next, we prepare to pour the sauce on top
# 将倒出的汁水放入锅中烧开
Add the liquid we just poured out to the pot and boil
# 烧开之后加入适量的水淀粉把汤汁收浓
After it boils, add some water starch to make the sauce thicker
# 同学们注意收汁的时候必须锅离火
Make sure the pot is away from the stove at this step
# 否则汤汁收不紧
Otherwise the sauce wouldn't become thicker
# 汤汁收浓之后加入少许明油
After the sauce is ready, add some Ming You (literally "brightening oil")
# 最后均匀的淋在肘子上面即可上菜
Finally, evenly pour on the knuckle and the dish is ready to be served
# 一道非常美味的扣肘子就制作完成
We've just made an extraordinarily delicious dish, braised pork knuckle
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, let's summarize the techniques
# 第一，肘子最好选择大一些的，这样成菜更加饱满
First, pick larger knuckles so that the dish looks better
# 第二，不方便宽油炸的同学可以忽略这一步
Secondly, the step to fry the knuckle with Kuan You can be ignored
# 第三，蒸制的时间越长口感约软嫩
Thirdly, the longer we steam, the more tender it tastes
# 扣肘子的技术总结完毕
Above is all techniques for braised pork knuckle